I do not often find myself in the habit
of thanking Elon Musk but I must confess
that he has done an exceptional job of
demonstrating a point that a few of us
have been making for years and that is
the reality that we live in an
oligarchic society in which billionaires
dominate not only our politics and the
information we consume from media but
our government and economic lives as
well that has never been clearer than it
is today by giv the news and attention
Mr musk has been getting over the last
few weeks as he illegally and
unconstitutionally dismantles government
agencies I think it is an appropriate
time to ask the question that the media
and most politicians don't seem to be
asking what do he and other
multi-billionaires really want what is
their endgame in my opinion what musk
and those around them are aggressively
striving for is not
it is not complicated and it is not new
it is what ruling classes throughout
history have always wanted and have
always believed is theirs by right more
power more control and more wealth and
they don't want Ordinary People that's
you and democracy getting in their way
they want it all Eli musk and his fellow
oligarchs believe government and laws
are simply an impediment an impediment
to their interests and what they are
entitled to entitled to in
pre-revolutionary America before the
1770s the ruling class governed through
a Doctrine called The Divine rights of
Kings the belief that the king of
England was an agent of God and he was
not to be questioned by mere mortals in
modern times we no longer have the
divine right of kings what we now have
is an ideology being pushed by the
oligarchs which says that as very very
wealthy people often self-made often as
the masters of revolutionary new
technology it is their absolute right to
rule in other words these modern-day
oligarchs are our Kings and it is not
just power it's incredible wealth that
they have today Mr musk is worth 402
billion Zuckerberg is worth 252 billion
Bezos is worth
249 billion with combined wealth of over
$900
billion these three people three people
own more wealth than the bottom half of
American society not surprisingly since
Trump was elected their wealth has
soared musk has become a 100 $138
billion richer Zuckerberg has become 49
billion richer and Bezos has become 28
billion richer all since election
day meanwhile while the very rich become
much richer 60% of Americans live
paycheck to paychecks 85 million are
uninsured or underinsured 25% of seniors
are trying to survive on $15,000
year or less
800,000 are homeless and we have the
highest rate of childhood Poverty of
almost any major country on Earth do you
think for one second that the oligarchs
give a damn about working people trust
me they don't musk's decision to
dismember us Aid means that tens of
thousands of the poorest people around
the world will go hungry or die of
preventable diseases but it's not just
abroad here in the United States they
will soon be going after the health care
nutrition housing and educational
programs that protect the most
vulnerable people in our country all so
that Congress can provide huge tax
breaks for them and their fellow
billionaires as modern-day Kings who
believe they have the absolute right to
rule they will sacrifice without
hesitation the well-being of working
people to protect their interests
further they will use the enormous media
operations they own to deflect attention
away from the impact of their policies
while they entertain us to death Mr musk
owns Twitter Mr Zuckerberg owns meta
which includes Facebook and Instagram
and Mr Bezos owns the Washington post
and twitch further they and their fellow
oligarchs will continue to spend huge
amounts of money to buy politicians in
both major political parties bottom line
the alars with their enormous resources
are waging a war against the working
class of this country and it is a war
that they are intent on winning now I'm
not going to kid you
the problems this country faces right
now are extremely serious the economy is
rigged our campaign Finance system is
corrupt and we are struggling to control
climate change and existential threat to
our planet among many many other
important issues but this is what I do
know the worst fear that the r ruling
class in this country has is that said
Americans black white Latino urban and
rural gay and straight young and old
that all of us will come together to
demand a government that represents all
of the people in our country not just
the wealthy few the oligarch nightmare
is that we will not allow ourselves to
be divided up by race religion sexual
orientation or country of origin and
will together have the courage to take
them on will this struggle be easy
absolutely not and one of the reasons
for that is that the ruling class of
this country will constantly remind you
that they have all the power they
control the government they own the
media you want to take us on Good Luck
they will say there is nothing you can
do about it but our job right now in
these very difficult times is to not
forget the great struggles and
sacrifices that millions of people have
waged over the several centuries to
create a more democratic just and Humane
Society think about it over the last
number of centuries how many people have
stood up and fought and when they were
doing that you know what their
contemporaries said they said hey you
want to overthrow the king King of
England to create a new nation and
self-rule forget about it
impossible you want to establish
Universal sufferage right of all people
to vote impossible can't happen you want
to end slavery and segregation
impossible you want to Grant workers the
right to form unions and end child labor
can't be done impossible you want to
give women control over their own bodies
who you kiding impossible can't be done
you want to pass legislation to
establish Social Security Medicare
Medicaid at minimum wage clean air and
water standards
impossible in other
words as Nelson Mandela told us
everything is
impossible until it is
done in these difficult times despair is
not an option we've got to fight back in
every way we can we have to get involved
in the political process run for office
connect with our local state and federal
legislators donate the candidates who
will fight for the working class in this
country we have got to create new
channels for communication and
information sharing we have to volunteer
not just politically but to build
community
locally whatever we can do is what we
must do needless to say I intend to do
my part both inside the Beltway and
traveling throughout the country to
stand up for working families and to
take on the oligarchy in the days weeks
and months ahead I hope you will join me
in that struggle we can win we will win
we must win thank you very much