thanks very much for joining me we are
living in a dangerous and unprecedented
moment in American history and I'm
getting a lot of calls from people who
are not only upset about what's
happening but are wondering how we best
go forward well let me tell you we've
got to be smart we've got to be
organized and we've got to fight back
this is not a time for wallowing in
Despair and hiding under the covers the
stakes are just too high we are not just
fighting for ourselves we're fighting
for our kids for future Generations
we're fighting for the future of this
planet in the first two weeks of his
presidency Donald Trump defied the
Constitution by ending Birthright
citizenship fired government Watchdogs
allowed drilling along our coastlines
pen violent insurrectionist suspended
all foreign aid and tried to cut off
virtually all federal funding so how do
we go forward first to be effective
we've got to understand what in fact is
happening around us right now second we
need a short-term strategy what do we do
tomorrow and the next day and the day
after that third we need a long-term
strategy how do we build a movement that
gains political power here is in my view
a brief overview as to what is happening
under Trump most
importantly the move toward oligarchy in
our country government run by the rich
and the powerful is proceeding rapidly
and it's not being done secretly a
little over a week ago Donald Trump was
inaugurated for his second term standing
right behind them with the three richest
men in the world Elon Musk Jeff Bezos
and Mark Zuckerberg men who have become
over $2 billion do richer since Trump
was elected and who now are worth almost
a trillion dollar more money than the
bottom half of American society
70 million people but it's not just
oligarchy that we should worry about
this country under Trump is moving
rapidly toward
authoritarianism just a few examples in
violation of the Constitution and
federal law Trump attempted the other
day to suspend all federal grants and
loans that means he blocked funding for
Medicaid head food stamps homeless
veterans etc etc tens of millions of
Americans some of the most vulnerable
people in our country were impacted by
that decision fortunately Americans all
across the country stood up in Outrage
and said no no and with the help of the
courts much but not all of that Freez
and funding was rescinded you may have
noticed that Trump is intimidating the
media with lawsuits against ABC CBS meta
and the De Moine register if Trump does
not like what media reports he is
threatening them with lawsuits
undermining the first amendment that is
a direct movement toward
authoritarianism now that's a very broad
overview of where we are today in terms
of short-term strategy we've got to
mobilize as strongly as we can against
Trump's dangerous proposals and let me
just say this
importantly yes the Republicans control
the house and the Senate but do not
forget their majorities are small in the
house a body of 435 members they have a
four vote majority that is a Raaz within
margin and their legislation can be
defeated there are a number of
Republicans out there who won in
Democratic districts by small margin so
let me tell you these guys do respond to
phone calls and emails so if there's a
piece of legislation you disagree with
get on the phone and call the capital
switchboard at 202 224
2131 and what is some of that
legislation that we should be concerned
about Republicans right now are working
on what's called a budget reconciliation
Bill the most important element which
the most important element which would
be a massive tax break for the wealthy
to be paid for by large Cuts in Medicaid
and other programs that Working Families
and low-income people desperately need
at a time of unprecedented Ed income and
wealth inequality when so many of our
people are struggling to put food on the
table we must not Savage programs for
Working Families to provide huge tax
breaks for
billionaires we must vigorously oppose
Trump's efforts at Mass
deportation yes we must strengthen our
borders yes we should Deport people who
have been convicted of serious crimes
but no no we cannot destroy families who
have lived and worked in this country
peacefully for decades not only is
Trump's Mass deportation program immoral
it will have a severely negative impact
on our
economy as all of you know we are seeing
extreme weather disturbances and
Devastation in our country and all over
the world related to climate change
think about La think about North
Carolina we must vigorously oppose this
absurd drill baby drill Doctrine which
will only make an incredibly dangerous
climate situation even worse and those
are just a few of the issues that are
coming down the pike but we cannot just
play defense we have got to be on the
offense please never forget that the
agenda that we are fighting for is
widely supported widely supported by
Working Families all across this country
and we must continue to fight for that
agenda the American people do not want
cuts to Medicaid and the privatization
of Medicare they understand that healthc
care is a human right not a privilege we
must continue the struggle for Medicare
for all so that every American has the
health care that he or she needs that's
not a radical idea that's what Americans
want federal minimum wage of 7 and a/ qu
an hour is a starvation wage we must
raise that minimum wage to a living wage
at least $17 an hour if you work 40
hours a week in America you should not
be living in poverty all over this
country we have a major housing crisis
and it's not just 800,000 who are
homeless it is millions of working
families who are spending 40 50 60% of
their limited incomes on housing instead
of spending almost a trillion dollars a
year on a wasteful and Bloated Pentagon
budget we have got to build millions of
units of low income and affordable
housing and when we do that we put large
numbers of people to work at good paying
union jobs I could go on and on
but let me conclude by saying this the
United States is the wealthiest nation
in the history of the world if we stand
together and oppose right-wing efforts
to divide us up by our Race by our
religion our sexual orientation or where
we were born if we stand together there
is nothing that we cannot accomplish
bottom line let us go forward and fight
for a government and an economy that
works for all not just a few we simply
do do not have the luxury of moaning and
groaning we have got to stand up and
fight back we can do it let's go forward
together thank you very much