thanks very much for joining me Uh
tonight we're going to do a bad news
good news routine So stay with me We
start off with the bad news which is
pretty bad but we are going to get to a
happier ending Uh let me begin by just
uh telling you what you already know and
that is that under Donald Trump this
country is h hurtling rapidly toward
oligarchy toward
authoritarianism toward
kleptocracy and toward more and more
income and wealth inequality That is
what is happening Uh you'll all remember
uh that Abraham Lincoln talked about a
government of the people by the people
and for the people I think it is very
clear that today we have a government of
the billionaire class by the billionaire
class and for the billionaire class Elon
Musk contributed
$277 million to get Donald Trump elected
president and he was
rewarded with the most important
position in government In other words he
put out the money and he got what he
paid for Trump also nominated 13 other
billionaires to head various government
agencies So almost all the guys who are
running the government are billionaires
For many years as I think you know I
have been talking about how a country is
moving toward an oligarchic form of
society And I know that people had their
doubts What is Bernie talking about well
not anymore Uh people now see what's
going on right in front of them No
secrets about it They're seeing the
billionaire class running our government
right now But it's not just oligarchy
and a government of the very rich that
I'm concerned about It is a very rapid
movement toward
authoritarianism Virtually every day
Trump is usurping the powers of Congress
He is ending programs that Congress
appropriated and he's getting rid of
agencies that he has no power to get rid
of Further he has sued major media
outlets like ABC CBS Meta and the De Mo
Register for stories and actions that he
didn't like And now his FCC is
investigating PBS and
NPR and he's threatening to withhold
federal funding for these vitally
important media outlets This is clearly
a massive attack on the First Amendment
and freedom of expression He doesn't
like what some media are saying and he
is intimidating them The message is
clear Hey I'm the boss Don't you dare
criticize me But it's not just Congress
and the media that he's going after He's
also waging a massive attack against the
judicial system
Unbelievably he is actually trying to
impeach judges who render decisions that
he doesn't
like Think about it Very few people who
are watching this discussion tonight
thought that the Supreme Court's
decision on Citizens United or Roie Wade
were good decisions In fact in my view
they were disastrous decisions But we're
kind of old-fashioned We believe in the
rule of law That's what happened
Presidents appointed those people to the
Supreme Court We didn't go around saying
"Hey you got to impeach Chief Justice
Roberts and the other members." Terrible
decision That's not the way the American
Constitution works and that's what we
believe We actually believe in the
Constitution But it's not just Congress
or the media or the judiciary that Trump
is going after He's now waging a
vitriolic attack against major
universities that are teaching courses
or allowing activities he doesn't like
For years we have heard conservatives
talk about decentralized government
getting the government off the backs of
the people We've heard about education
being a local issue And now we have a
president who is telling Harvard
Colombia Princeton and others what they
can or cannot do And in an absolutely
unconstitutional and frightening way
federal agents have grabbed foreign
students thrown them into unmarked cars
and taken them to detention
facilities And what is their crime what
have they done that deserves that kind
of treatment well in at least one case
uh a woman wrote uh a article critical
of Israel In another case somebody
attended a demonstration Do you really
grab people off of the street throw them
in unmarked cars take them to detention
centers because they expressed a
political point of view and unbelievably
he is now going after law firms that
oppose them Giant law firms Can you
imagine a president threatening a law
firm because they represented a client
or did something that you don't like
and Trump has also decided that he needs
to lead the culture war in America He
has made himself chairman of the board
of the Kennedy
Center So if you add all of these
activities up and I'm just talking about
a small part of what he has done it
makes one thing very very clear Trump
has very little respect for the
Constitution of the United States and
for the rule of law He wants more and
more power for himself and his fellow
billionaires He wants to lead an
authoritarian
nation And to make a bad situation even
worse Trump and Musk are rapidly trying
to dismember and destroy federal
agencies that serve working families and
the poor Musk has laid off thousands of
workers at the Social Security
Administration which will make it harder
for the elderly and the disabled to get
the benefits that they paid for It's a
massive attack against Social Security
Trump and Musk have also decided to lay
off some
83,000 employees at the Veterans
Administration which will mean that the
men and women who put their lives on the
line to defend our country our veterans
will see a deterioration in the health
care they receive at the VA and the
timeliness of the benefits that they
earned And then on top of all of that
Trump and his Republican colleagues are
now working on a huge reconciliation
bill which will make massive cuts to
Medicaid education nutrition etc to do
what why are they making these cuts in
order to give over a trillion dollars in
tax breaks to the
1% So that's where we are That is the
bad news and all in all it is a pretty
dismal
situation So now let me give you some
good news some very good news and that
is over the last month I and my house
colleague uh Alexandria
Kaziocortez have been traveling the
country in what I've called a fighting
oligarchy tour I've been to Nebraska
Iowa Wisconsin Michigan Nevada Colorado
and Arizona and the turnouts have been
extraordinary Uh in Denver we had more
than
34,000 people turn out the largest rally
I have ever been a part of And what I
have learned from all of these rallies
and meeting thousands and thousands of
people is that the people of our country
are sick and tired of Trumpism They are
tired of oligarchy They are tired of
authoritarianism and they are prepared
to fight back And I should tell you just
just to mention I'm going to be in uh
out west uh next week uh in a week and a
half or so We're going to California and
other western states and we are going to
continue to rally the American people to
stand up to Trumpism and his contempt
for American democracy And let me give
you another very good piece of good news
and and that is on Tuesday night uh
Susan Crawford uh took on Elon Musk and
the $25 million that he spent to win a
seat on the Wisconsin Supreme Court And
I want you all to remember that just
five months ago uh Trump won a narrow
victory in Wisconsin And just the other
day Miss Crawford won a strong victory
She won by 10 points Pretty good victory
in a state that Trump had won just five
months before Also on Tuesday night in
two congressional districts in Florida
where Trump had won by 30 points
Democratic candidates while losing cut
that margin in half Pretty good So where
do we go from here
uh I think the answer is quite obvious
We have got to educate We've got to
organize We've got to fight back
effectively with discipline and
intelligence And if we do that in my
view we're going to win this thing And
right now I should tell you we are not
only doing rallies around the country We
are also hiring organizers at the
grassroots level to help us build the
kind of grassroots infrastructure that
we need if we're going to be successful
And let me just mention to you uh that
just a few hours ago uh I was on the
phone with our friends in the first
district of Iowa I had been to Iowa City
uh last month and we got a whole lot of
folks coming out Uh we got names we got
emails we called them up and we had
tonight just a few hours ago over 500
people in the first district of Iowa on
the telephone and almost all of them
signed up to get to work to help us
organize to knock on doors to hold
meetings etc And we are going to have
organizers all over this country
especially in districts where Republican
members of Congress won by slim
majorities And we're going to make sure
that all of the people in those
districts that were won by Republicans
with small margins they know loudly and
clearly they're going to hear from their
constituents that they must not vote to
give huge tax breaks to billionaires by
cutting Medicaid and other programs that
working families desperately need So yes
let me be very honest with you Uh the
oligarchs are enormously powerful No ifs
buts and may They have endless amounts
of money They control our economy They
own much of the media And they have
enormous influence over our political
system But from the bottom of my heart I
am convinced that if we are smart and if
we're well organized they can be
defeated If we stand together and not
let them divide us up by the color of
our skin or where we were born or our
religion or our sexual orientation If we
bring our people together around an
agenda that works for the many and not
just the few there is nothing in the
world that can stop us We can win We
will win So let us go forward together
Let's build that movement that we
desperately need Let's defeat Trumpism
Thank you all very much